Guide to the Frederick Emmons Terman Papers SC0160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Addenda, 1984; Series XIV
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence by Year
    - Sept. - Dec. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - May - Aug. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - May - June 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - July - Aug. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sept. - Oct. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nov. - Dec. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Apr. - June 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - July - Sept. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Apr. - June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - July - Sept. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Jan. - Mar. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Apr. - June 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - July - Sept. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Oct. - Dec. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - May - Aug. 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - May - Aug. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jan. - Apr. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - May - Aug. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Sept. - Dec. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jan. - June 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - July - Dec. 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Jan. - June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - July - Dec. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Index to Correspondence, 8/65 10/69 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence by Subject
    - Misc. Correspondence. "A" (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Academic Council, 1959 - 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Academic Council, 9/15/72 - 1/14/74 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Academic Council, 4/l/74 - 1/6/75 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Academic Council, 3/26/75 - 12/12/77 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Academic Planning Office (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Administrative Policies, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Administrative Policies, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Administrative Policies, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Policies, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Policies, 1975-76 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Admissions (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - A.S.E.E. - General (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Association for Continuing Education (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Correspondence. "B" (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Brooks, E. Howard (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Budget (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Business School (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Misc. Correspondence "C" (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Caldwell, Dave (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Center for Materials Research (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Chemistry Department (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Civil Engineering Department (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Classified Research (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Computer Science (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Corporate Friends (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Cullum, Allen W. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Cuthbertson, Kenneth M. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Correspondence "D" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Davis, Paul H., 1947-70 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Paul H., 1971-77 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Correspondence "E" (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Earth Sciences (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Education School (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Electrical Engineering Department (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Emeritus Professors (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Engineering School Newsletters (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Engineering School - Misc., 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Engineering School - Misc., 1974-78 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1975-76 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1977-78 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1979-80 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Engineering Advisory Council, 1980-81 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Engineering Management (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - English for Engineering Students (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - ERIC: Educational Resources Information Center (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Misc. Correspondence "F" (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Study (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Fringe Benefits (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Correspondence "G" (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - General Secretary (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Ginzton Laboratory (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Dean of Graduate Studies (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Correspondence "H" (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Heffner, Hubert (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Hewlett, Walter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Honors Cooperative Program (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Hoover Isolationism Episode (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Housing (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Correspondence "I" (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - IBM (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - IEEE Life Members (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Industrial Engineering Department (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Industrial Relations (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Institute for Energy Studies (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Misc. Correspondence "J" (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Correspondence "K" (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Kays, William M. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Misc. Correspondence "L" (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Land Development Projects (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Libraries (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Linvill, John (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lyman, Richard E. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Correspondence "M" (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - McCullough Space (Rm. 174 - 176) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - McDermott, Mary (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mechanical Engineering Department (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miller, William (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Correspondence "N" (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - NASA (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Medal of Science (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - National Institutes of Health (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Correspondence "O" (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Correspondence "P" (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - School of Engineering Placement Report, 1969-70 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Planning and Placement Center: Employment of (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Planning and Budget Committee Report (Task Force VI) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Correspondence "R" (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Research Programs and Costs (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Retirement Plan Study (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - ROTC, NROTC, AFROTC (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Correspondence "S" (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Salary Information (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - San Jose State Cybernetics Program (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Security (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Shockley, William (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Skilling, Hugh H. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - SLAC (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Stanford Associates (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Sterling, Wallace (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Strong Vocational Test (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Students, Prospective (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Correspondence "T" (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Tarr, Curtis (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Tau Beta Pi (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Correspondence "U" (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - United Stanford Employees (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Correspondence "V" (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Correspondence "W" (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Visitors and Guests at Stanford (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Correspondence "XYZ" (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Yu, Frank and Philip (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Stanford PACE Program Correspondence
    - Correspondence "A" (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "B" (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Boswell Foundation (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Briggs, Mitzi (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Bulletins (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Bulletins (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "C" (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Campaign for Stanford (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Coberly, C.J. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Components of Campaign (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence "D" (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - DuPont (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence "E" (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Eitel, William (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Engineering Affiliates (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence "F" (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Foundations (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "G" (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Gerstley, James (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Gifts (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - General Prospects (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "H" (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and World, Inc. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Havas, George (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Hurd, C.C. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "I" (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - IBM (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "J" (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "K" (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Kennedy Foundation (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "L" (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "M" (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - McBean, Atholl (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - McClatchy (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - McCullough (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - McMicking (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Meetings, 1961-62 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Meetings, 1961-62 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-63 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-66 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Morell, George (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Motorola, Inc. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Muhs Foundation, 1957-62 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Muhs Foundation, 1963-67 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Muhs Foundation, 1968-72 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Muhs Foundation, 1973-76 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Muhs Foundation, 1977-80 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "N" (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "O" (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Olin Foundation (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "P" (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Peterson, T.F. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1959-61 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1961-62 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Pfeiffer Foundation, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Polhemus Fund (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Procter and Gamble (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Professorships (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Puls, Louis (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "R" (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Regional Dinners (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Regional Meetings (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "S" (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "S" (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Sloan Foundation (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Standard Oil of California (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Cabinet (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Stauffer, John (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Stauffer, John (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Swim, Dudley (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Syntex (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "T" (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Tax Considerations (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "U" (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Union Carbide (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "V" (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Varian (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "W" (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Stanford PACE Program: Long Range Planning
    - Academic Goals and Financial Needs, 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Academic Needs (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Background Data for Financial Needs (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Background Data for Financial Needs, 1960-70 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Background Data for Financial Needs, 1960-70 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Building Space Improvements (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Building Space Improvements (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Building Space Improvements (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Expenditures (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Expansion (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Financial Needs (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Plan of Campaign, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Private Gift Support (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Article: "Changing Needs for PhD's" (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Articles, Information Sheets, and Publications (Box 18)
    - Article: "Economic Factors Relating to Engineering Programs" (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Article: "Steeples of Excellence" (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Article: "Steeples of Excellence" (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Article: "Supply of Scientific and Engineering Manpower (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Bay Area Electronics Industry (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Building Plans and Information (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Building Plans and Information (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Campus Maps (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Cost of Student Instruction (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Cost of Student Instruction: Faculty (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Electronics Education (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Engineering B.S. Candidates (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Engineering Research Objectives (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - History of Electrical Engineering Education (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Articles, Information Sheets and Publications
    - Miscellaneous Speeches and Addresses, 1977-78 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Tutored Videotape Instruction (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Engineering Students
    - PhD Candidates, 1960-61 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - PhD Candidates, 1961-62 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - PhD Candidates, 1962-63 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - PhD Candidates, 1963-64 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - PhD Candidates, 1964-65 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - PhD Candidates, 1964-65 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - PhD Candidates, 1965-66 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - PhD Candidates, 1966-67 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - PhD Candidates, 1967-68 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - PhD Candidates, 1968-69 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - PhD Candidates, 1969-70 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - PhD Candidates, 1970-71 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - PhD Candidates, 1971-72 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - PhD Candidates, 1972-73 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - PhD Candidates, 1973-74 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - PhD Candidates, 1974-75 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - PhD Candidates, 1975-76 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - PhD Candidates, 1976-77 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - PhD Candidates, 1977-78 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Engineering Degrees and Enrollments, 1964-71 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Engineering Degrees and Enrollments, 1972-73 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Technological Corporations
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Granger Associates (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Hewlett Packard Monthly Reports, Jan - Apr 1978 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Hewlett Packard Monthly Reports, May - Aug 1978 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Hewlett Packard Monthly Reports, Sep - Nov 1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Hewlett Packard Annual Reports 1977-78 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Hewlett Packard: Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Watkins-Johnson Co. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Reports on High Technology Activities in Northern California, 1972-73 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Reports on High Technology Activities in Northern California, 1974-75 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Reports on High Technology Activities in Northern California, 1975-76 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Report on Minorities in Engineering, Part 1 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Report on Minorities in Engineering, Part 2 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Report on Minorities in Engineering, Part 3 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Terman Office Materials
    - F.E. Terman's Office Manual (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Appointment Book, 9/71 - 9/72 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Appointment Book, 9/72 - 9/73 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Appointment Book, 9/73 - 9/74 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Appointment Book, 9/74 - 9/75 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Appointment Book, 9/75 - 9/76 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Appointment Book, 9/78 - 9/79 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Appointment Book, 9/76 - 9/77 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Large Size Folders
    - Three Quarter Summary of Enrollment, 1968-69 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Registration Statistics, 1963-78 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Summer Enrollment, 1969-70 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH.2002-286
  - Frederick E. Terman Ph. D. dissertation at MIT: Characteristics and Stability of transmission systems (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2017-017
  Scope and Contents
  Letters and contracts between Frederick E. Terman, McGraw-Hill, and the Stanford University Board of Trustees regarding Terman's transfer of publication rights of Radio Engineers' Handbook to Stanford University.
  - Correspondence and contracts, 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Deed to Alturas Drive property, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)